Charles A. and June R. P. Ross Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
- Miscellaneous, Series II
  - Correspondence., 002771
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1963 - Two unsigned letters from C.A. Ross to G.A. Cooper sent in thanks of support for Ross' West Texas fusulinid studies, informing Cooper of his election as a Fellow of the Geological Society of America (GSA); one postcard from GSA to Ross acknowledging receipt of manuscript submission; one letter from Marsha Young to Ross regarding copyright details from Ross' GSA manuscript submission (with handwritten notes by Young asking for a signed copy of Ross' "Standard Wolfcampian Series."); one typewritten synopsis of Ross' Standard Wolfcampian Series, published in Science (v. 141, no. 3578, p.345-346) and written by C.C. Albritton, Jr., 003106
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1963 - One letter from C.A. Ross to R.H. Hansman in response to inquries about several specimens appearing in Ross&Ross (1963) and Sabins and Ross (1963; see Associations Tab)., 003108
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1963-1964 - One letter from C.A. Ross to Bruce Pearson (Independent Geologist) expressing thanks for sending his authored article from the Oil and Gas Journal (regarding hydrocarbon potential of the Marfa Basin, West Texas); short, partial reprint of B. Pearson's article on the Marfa Basin's hydrocarbon potential, including a then out-of-date interpretation of Paleozoic structures in West Texas, annotated with comments by B. Pearson., 002897
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1964 - One letter from C.A. Ross to Bruce Pearson (Independent Geologist) expressing thanks, his inability to attend Pearson's field trip in Chihuahua, Mexico and his move to Western Washington State College., 002898
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1964 - 6 pages of unpublished thoughts by B. Pearson sent in correspondence between C.A. Ross and B. Pearson regarding regional relationships of Paleozoic-Recent strata in West Texas and Mexico., 002899
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1964-1965 - Correspondence between Charles A. Ross and A.J. Wells, pertaining to two sections measured from Wells' M.S. thesis (conferred by University of Arizona) on the topic of Mid-Penn fusulinids from the Naco Formation, SE Arizona. Specimen photography from both sections is included as well as a figure copy (Figure 2) from Wells' thesis., 002776
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1964-1965 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and A.J. Wells pertaining to Ross' willingness to look at some fusulinid slides on Wells' behalf. Ross notes in the later letter (Feb 1965) of his intentions to send wells a reprint of a paper once published to the J. of Paleontology (pertaining to the association between Profusulinella and Fusulinella)., 003082
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1966 - Five letters exchanged between C.A. Ross and P.K. Link discussing the transfer of hand (bulk-rock) samples collected by P. Link to C.A. Ross, in efforts towards co-authorship of a Penn/Perm fusulinid paper between the two. The aforementioned hand samples are sourced from collections by P. Link in pursuit of his Ph.D. at University of Wisconsin., 003007
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1969 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and May Dasch concerning questions related to fusulinids to be sent on loan by the Peabody Museum of Natural History, originally collected by C.A. Ross and Sabins in 1966 (Permian Fusulinids from El Paso Mountains, California: Journal of Paleontology, v.40, p. 155-161). The letter sent from Dasch to Ross has a xeroxed and typewritten copy; the xeroxed copy has answers written into blanks, by C.A. Ross, originally included in the original letter from Dasch; see Associations tab for specimen photography originally enclosed with correspondence., 003075
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1969 - One letter from J.B. Waterhouse seeking C.A. Ross' clarification on age determinations and biozone interpretations presented in his Memoir 88 (Neal Ranch and Lenox Hills formations) which were correlated with the Asselian [Early Permian]., 003086
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross and J.N. Conley - 1973 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and J.N. Conley regarding hydrocarbon occurrences within the state of Arizona; contains two letters and an information source booklet on exploration for energy resources in the state of Arizona., 002861
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1974 - Correspondence and specimen photography of fusulinids from three sections [BH-1, BH-2 and BH-3; stratigraphic columns included] exchanged between Charles A. Ross, University of Arizona graduate student Molly Dolldoff and her thesis adviser, Donald L. Bryant spanning 6 February through 2 July, 1974., 002780
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1980 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and J.L. Hannah regarding analysis of 8 thin sections from the upper Peale chert breccia, possibly from the Peale Fm. (or overlying Fm, Sierra Nevadas, California)., 003084
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross and Thompson, S. - 1981 - Correspondence between Sam Thompson and parties interested in petroleum geology of SW New Mexico; contains one memo (#2) and the first page of two publications showcasing Thompson's newest publication releases (1981)., 002862
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1981-1984 - handwritten and typed correspondence between C.A. Ross and E. Konopka regarding the identification of fusulinids within problematic Oquirrh Grp. (Butterfield Peaks and Edna formations) age control for sections needed towards the completion of Konopka's research; includes copies of sample lists, figure drafts and stratigraphic columns drawn by either Ross or Konopka., 003185
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1983 - Two letters sent between June Ross and Brian Norford, discussing the return of original plates from a manuscript (Norford et al, bulletin 267) to C.A. Ross after publication; includes 9 plates, mounted on cardboard. The exact publication from which these plates were published has not yet been determined (although it's derived from Contributions to Canadian Paleontology: Geological Survey of Canada, Bulletin 267)., 002910
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1996 - Two letters sent between J.R. Ross and Bruce Wardlaw and David Rohr (with C.A. Ross using June's email), including 1) Charlie's wanting to meet a man named Ernest in Bellingham [state?] before the Guadalupian Symposium in Alpine, TX and 2) a reply from D. Rohr to C.A. Ross explaining B. Wardlaw's intention to publish the Guadalupian Symposium II information as a type of USGS publication in the future., 002912
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1985 - One copy of a handwritten letter sent from Sam Thompson to Frank Kottlowski in review of a paper co-authored by C.A. Ross and J.R. Ross titled "Paleozoic Paleotectonics and Sedimentation in the Southern Rocky Mountain Region.", 003184
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1989 - Correspondence between Professor Joe Schreiber, Jr. of University of Arizona's Department of Geoscience and Charles A. Ross pertaining to Ross' being allowed to attend a Whetstone Mountains field trip in SE Arizona, per Chevron's operational needs., 002772
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1990 - One letter summarizing findings from a litholog report completed for a well drilled in Brewster County, Texas [Madre Grande #1; see Associations tab], sent to James Cearly in Houston (other two parties are CC'ed in correspondence)., 003024
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1990-1991 - Correspondence between Charles A. Ross and Gerilyn (Lynn) Soreghan [Andrews = Maiden name], graduate student[?] at University of Arizona (as of 1990-1991), pertaining to various sections from Arizona (including the Pedregosa, Dragoon, Chiricahua and San Andres mountains; Naco Hills) measured by Soreghan and sent to Ross asking for foraminiferal identification and age determinations; handwritten sample list; 1 copy of abstract form for completed research (submitted for a GSA meeting in 1990); 1 copy of an M.S. Thesis from the University of Arizona (Sue Ann Reid, 1972). Photocopies of stratigraphic sections and field notes from the Dragoon and Chiricahua mountains and Naco Hills., 002775
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1990-2006 - Two letters between C.A. Ross and C. MacClintock regarding request/acquisition of supporting documentation for C.A. Ross' fusulinid collections., 003091
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1996 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and two parties, Roger Kaesler (University of Kansas Paleontological Institute) and Alice Hart (University of Kansas Natural History Museum) regarding the whereabouts of thin section descriptions and locality lists from J. Skinner sent to the University of Kansas upon closure of Exxon's Midland office. C.A. Ross, amidst reevaluating and reinterpreting fusulinid faunas of the Hess Limestone, requested this information to further his study; one list of Exxon localities sent from A. Hunt to C.A. Ross one week after their initial correspondence., 003065
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1997-2006 - Correspondence between Charles A. Ross and Tim White, Copeland MacClintock of the Division of Invertebrate Paleontology, Peabody Museum of Natural History, Yale University pertaining to Ross' collection localities spanning 1965-1968 in Arizona and New Mexico, as well as sample collections from Floyd F. Sabins' Portal section (SE Arizona)., 002774
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross and Spencer G. Lucas - 1998 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and S.G. Lucas regarding the position of various measured sections in New Mexico derived from M.L. Thompson's Pennsylvanian-age sections [1942]. Includes annotations by S.G. Lucas of a few 1:100,000 scale topographic maps marking potential localities later investigated by C.A. Ross; one copy of Lucas et al., 2000, titled "Lithostratigraphy and Fusulinaceans of the Type Section of the Bursum Fm, Upper Carboniferous of South-Central New Mexico.", 002781
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 2014-2015 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and M. Dvorzak, librarian at the C. K. Leith Library of Geology and Geophysics, University of Wisconsin-Madison regarding C.A. Ross' wishes to obtain Peter Link's 1965 Ph.D. dissertation; correspondence between C.A. Ross and an individual by the name of "Judy" at Bellingham (WA) Public Library concerning a potential interlibrary loan of Peter Link's dissertation; handwritten notes and information on indviduals named Peter K. Link in the midwest/west USA; handwritten lists of individuals C.A. Ross intended to contact to get a hold of Peter Link's dissertation; one handwritten list of published articles generated by C.A. Ross., 003008
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - Several letters sent between C.A. Ross, B.S. Lieberman and U. Farrell inquiring 1) the fate of the Skinner and Wilde fusulinid collections at the University of Kansas, particularly those connected to fusulinid specimens and thin sections relating to the Atlin, British Columbia area and 2) about a list of localities where aforementioned specimens were collected; U. Farrell provided a list named "ExxonYukonLocs.xls" containing locality information on collections made by Skinner and Wilde while at Humble Oil Co. [later became Exxon and later still ExxonMobil]; a typeset copy of Yukon localities from the ExxonYukonLocs list., 003010
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 2017 - One letter sent from C.A. Ross to R. Staughter (Dept. of Geology, University of Wisconsin-Madison) pertaining to Ross' abandonment of a project originally intended to be a collaboration between C.A. Ross and Peter K. Link (based on Link's 1965 Ph.D. dissertation) and 1) his intentions to return specimens to UWISC's museum, if requested by Staughter and 2) to ask Staughter for advice on what to do with ~150 pounds of specimens from his thin section lab at Western Washington University and his intentions to close the lab indefinitely., 003009
    - Correspondence between June Ross and Enrico Serpagli; also a heavily marked up early draft of a manuscript "New evidence for perimetrical attachment organ in some Ordovician Trepostomatous Bryozoans" by Stefano Conti and Enrico Serpagli, 1983; 002875
  - Miscellaneous., 001259
    - Miscellaneous Locality Notes. Charles A. Ross - ca. 1980 - three pages of notes detailing localities or need to delve into literature for Permian-strata-related studies in Colorado; one roadmap of Colorado included with locality list., 003078
    - Miscellaneous. 7 lab notebooks and workbooks from June Ross' time at the University of Sydney as follows: Manual of Directions for use in Practical Biological Chemistry (2 copies), Agricultural Chemistry IIb - Soil Characteristics part 2 (1949), Agricultural Chemistry I - Quantitative Analysis: principles and application to some inorganic radicles of agricultural importance (1950), Agricultural Chemistry Ib - Practical surface and electro-chemistry (1950), Agricultural Chemistry IIb - Practical soil physics and chemistry part 1 (1951), Agricultural Biochemistry 1 - Animal physiology., 1949-1951; 003204
    - Miscellaneous. 4 pamphlets concerning Australia: "Select list of Australian books normally available from American sources. May-June 1965"; "Select list of Australian books normally available from American sources. June-July 1965"; "Australia decimal currency system"; "U.S.-Australian Financial Relations: Balance of Payments", 1965-1966; 003205
    - Miscellaneous. Documents pertaining to locations of various samples within cabinets. Annotated., 1999-2002; 002483
    - Miscellaneous. Documents pertaining to the establishment of the Charles A. and June R.P. Ross Endowment fund for the curation, management and study of the C.A. and J.R.P. Ross material and associated material., 1999; 000719
    - Miscellaneous. Charles A. Ross - 1980 and afterward - One list of references from Dave Rohr's PRI Proposal (Jul 1988) on W. Texas and the Glass Mts.; List of addresses, PO Boxes and contact information for various ranch owners within the Marathon Basin and Glass Mountains area, W. Texas., 003127
    - Miscellaneous. Charles A. Ross - 1996 - Miscellaneous notes, forms and info sheets related to a field trip held during the Guadalupian Symposium II, held at Sul Ross State University, Alpine, TX April 10-13, 1996; contact information for symposium participants; two photocopies of Guadalupian Ammonoid Ranges (Basinal Deposits, Guadalupe Mountains); graphic road map of Alpine, Texas., 002911
    - Miscellaneous. June R. P. Ross - Curriculum Vitae and publication list, 000934
    - Miscellaneous. Charles A. Ross - Partial Exxon Road Log for a trip to Trans-Pecos, Texas (Including the Glass, Del Norte, Dugout, Chinati mountains and Marathon, Alpine)., 003125
    - Miscellaneous. Miscellaneous documents including, but not limited to: notes from research trip to Penn State regarding Australians, locality information from Rt. 10 in Mason County Kentucky, stratigraphic information regarding sites from 6-5-64 and 6-6-64 and 6-10-64, AAPG abstract notes, references for sections, Spitsbergen locality notes, 003193
  - Publication material., 002482
    - Conference Registrant List. June R.P. Ross - August 4-9, 1986 - List of registrants for the International Bryozoology Association's 7th International Meeting at Western Washington University in Bellingham, Washington. 3 pp., 003004
    - Locality information. Photocopies of publications dealing with bryozoa collections: western New York. 1959, 1960, 000321
    - Notes and Funding Proposal Review. Charles A. Ross - 1983-1985 - Handwritten notes by C.A. Ross pertaining to work completed by L. McCollum, Jim Ellis and others pertaining to Paleozoic strata in Nevada; one copy of a funding proposal review sheet (completed by C.A. Ross) including supporting figures and a bibliography from L. McCollum and W.K. Steele's initial funding proposal to the Petroleum Research Fund., 003181
    - Notes and Illustrations. Charles A. Ross - Notes and illustrations related to C.A. Ross' attempt to resolve a multitude of discrepancies in the data, analysis and interpretation of various aspects of Peter K. Link's 1965 Ph.D. dissertation from University of Wisconsin; a synopsis (January 2015) of results from C.A. Ross' efforts to work with Link's dissertation including the list of problems identified within; reprinted and redrawn stratigraphic sections (C.A. Ross) including I, II, III and VI of Link's thesis; xeroxed copies of segments of Link's thesis accompanied with notes by C.A. Ross; scaled up reprints of figures 7 and 8 from Link's thesis with annotations from C.A. Ross., 1965-2015; 003005
    - Publication Material. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1973 - Figure drafts for Text Fig. 4 in Ross and Sabins (1965), figure 6 of Ross (1973); figure [?] of Ross (1973; sections 40 and 41 derived from Zeller, 1965); figure 8 of Sabins, 1957; handwritten stratigraphic column of the Big Hatchet Section, from the Big Hatchet Mountains, NM (drawn by C.A. Ross); one loose, inked segment of a strat column (McDonald Ranch [Section #38] of Ross (1973)); one 3x5" index card with annotations accompanied by a piece of yellow graph paper (similar size)., 002866
    - Publication Material. 1959. Two publications from 1959, published in the Arizona Geological Society Guidebook 2: Arizona Geological Society Digest by Neal E. McGlymonds (USGS), pages 66-84, pertaining to the Paleozoic stratigraphy of the Waterman Mountains (p. 66-76) and Precambrian and Paleozoic sedimentary rocks of the Papgo Indian Reservation, AZ (p. 77-84); one blank map order form from 1982., 002865
    - Publication Material. Figure drafts of Silurian outcrops in the United States, 002925
    - Publication Material; Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1987-1992 - Outcrop and Misc. photography sized and later published in a field guide from C.A. Ross, probably for his SEPM or Chevron field trip in 1987; contains 15 photographs used for figures. Some photos are from thumbnails or are elsewhere printed in color (see Associations Tab); 7 color, annotated photographs of outcrops and escarpments in the Glass Mountains, W. Texas taken between May-June 1992., 002908
    - Publication Material. Charles A. Ross - 1923-1961 - Assorted notes on Late Paleozoic (Carboniferous-Permian) stratigraphy and marine invertebrates (e.g., fusulinids, brachiopods, gastropods) from various regions worldwide (e.g., USSR, South Wales, southwestern USA, China). Some of this material is undoubtedly research conducted by C.A. Ross in his Ph.D. pursuits; includes global correlation charts for various invertebrates and Late Paleozoic stages; contains two photographs, one of plate 36 of a publication (undetermined) and one of a cross section of a foram (plate 7, Russian publication, unkown author)). Much of this material may also be related to Ross and Ross (1995), titled "Foraminiferal Zonation of late Paleozoic depositional sequences". Also includes a flyer for a field trip in Ciudad Victoria and Ciudad Valles areas of Mexico, to be held May 23-26 (year unknown; hosted by Bill Payne of Texaco, Inc.)., 002902
    - Publication Material. Charles A. Ross - 1945-1981 - 2 pages of handwritten notes by C.A. Ross on "Tectonics of Southeastern Arizona" by Harald D. Drewes; one reprint of the Oil and Gas Investigations Preliminary Chart 10 from Huddle and Dobravolny (1945), annotated by C.A. Ross, presumably during his own investigation of SE Arizona prior to the publication of his 1973 paper and/or synthesis of later publications., 002871
    - Publication Material. Charles A. Ross - 1957 and afterward - Various copies of Leonardian illustrations (photo, typewritten, vellum, etc.) including stratigraphic correlations, figures, maps (topographic, geologic), panorama views (drawings of Leonard Mt.)., 003126
    - Publication Material. Charles A. Ross - 1963-1997 - Figure photocopies of depositional sequences (Ross and Ross, Fig. 6; Hess LS Formation), Wolfcampian Stratigraphy (composite from Ross (1963), "Standard Wolfcampian Series" Figure 10), and Wolfcampian strata of Kansas (Baars et al., 1994a (Figure 2); 1994b (Figure 3)) with handwritten boundary notes., 003115
    - Publication Material. Charles A. Ross and Robert A. Zeller - 1965-1973 - Hand-drawn copies of stratigraphic columns by C.A. Ross derived from lithologic descriptions of sections published in "Stratigraphy of the Big Hatchet Mountains Area, New Mexico [R.A. Zeller, 1965]. These sections were later published as part of C.A. Ross' 1973 paper, including the Borrego [#40], Bugle Ridge [#41], Hale Tank and New Well Peak [#42] sections., 002870
    - Publication Material. Charles A. Ross - 1982 - Research results report titled "Progress Report of Research of the Geology of the Bull Run Mountains, Nevada," authored by Kenneth D. Ehman (Dept. Geology, UC Davis). There are multiple copies of this progress report; this particular copy belongs to C.A. Ross., 003158
    - Publication Material. Charles A. Ross - 1983 - Research results report titled "Analysis of Cenozoic and Pre-Tertiary Structures of the Hot Creek Valley Region, Central Arizona," authored by John S. Oldow (Dept. Geology, Rice University) as part of a research project sponsored by Gulf Oil Exploration and Production Company in 1983., 003157
    - Publication Material. Charles A. Ross - Latest 1982 - Figure drafts and copies of figures from publications relating to analysis of facies, biozones and stratal relationships between Penn/Perm formations in Nevada; copies of handdrawn sequence stratigraphic correlation of sections measured by Ross, Sabins and others., 003179
    - Publication Materials. Charles A. Ross - 1970-1987 - Hand-drawn stratigraphic columns, with 4 sourced from papers studying Egyptian stratigraphy (Penn/Perm) and 2 concerning Paleozoic stratigraphy from the Ural Mountains., 003015
    - Publication Materials. Charles A. Ross - 1976-1996 - Manuscript draft components (e.g., introduction), handwritten manuscript edits and notes, hand-drawn stratigraphic columns related to a potentially unpublished paper by C.A. Ross, titled, "Depositional History of Late Paleozoic Carbonate Succession in Northwestern British Columbia"; one copy of authorship guidelines for the Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences; figure (Fig. 1 and 2) revisions for a paper by Jim Monger and W.J. Nokleberg titled "Evolution of the northern North American Cordillera: generation, fragmentation, displacement and accretion of successive North American plate-margin arcs.", 003014
    - Publication Materials. Charles A. Ross and Jim G.H. Monger - 1976-? - Figure drafts, typed manuscript drafts with handwritten edits, typed and handwritten specimen locality/description notes and hand-drawn stratigraphic columns related to an unpublished[?] collaboration between C.A. Ross and J. G. Monger in the mid 1970s titled, "Carboniferous and Permian Reef Complex, Nakina Quadrangle, Northwestern British Columbia.", 003013
    - Publication/Research Material. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Various research notes, fusulinid identifications and references pertaining to collections, papers, books and other media published by many scientists in Europe and worldwide (including paleontologists from Switzerland, Poland, France, Italy, Tunisia, Norway, U.K., Germany, British Honduras and Borneo); includes few negatives of fusulinids from specimens collected in British Honduras., 003129
    - Publication/Research Source Material. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1974 - Copies of Pennsylvanian/Permian fusulinid plates from various publications collected and utilized by C.A. Ross in his studies of Penn/Perm strata in the western US (see Associations Tab)., 003156